<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Josh Rieken</title>
    <description>Software developer. Micropreneur. I love Elixir, Ruby, Neovim, RVing, and small things.
</description>
    <link>http://www.joshuarieken.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.joshuarieken.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 15:43:30 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 15:43:30 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Tell Little White Lies with Pivotal Tracker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://softwareforgood.com/estimates-lies/&quot;&gt;Estimates are always lies&lt;/a&gt;. But let’s forget about that for a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pivotaltracker.com&quot;&gt;Pivotal Tracker&lt;/a&gt; for many years and find that it still provides tremendous value. There’s an age-old debate: &lt;strong&gt;which story point method should I use when estimating?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the more important question is: What do those values mean? A little googling will quickly reveal that almost every developer has their own interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer the fibonacci sequence (0,1,2,3,5,8), and this is how I interpret it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0:&lt;/strong&gt; Trivial and directly affects and is noticeable by the user (e.g., fixing a typo, altering some copy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:&lt;/strong&gt; Everything is known, and the feature is straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:&lt;/strong&gt; Everything is known, and the feature has some complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a good idea of how to move forward, but there’s an integration or some other aspect that may add unforeseen complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5:&lt;/strong&gt; Too high-level and/or involves a large amount of complexity. Needs to be planned and possibly spiked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8:&lt;/strong&gt; Pie-in-the-sky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing above a 3 should ever be delivered.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, 5s and 8s should always be broken down. The resulting stories will often add up to more than 5 or 8. That’s ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I’d change about this process involves 5s and 8s. They should really be 20s and 50s to better reflect what they turn out to be in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember: estimates are always lies. However, they can be little white lies that help us come a little closer to the truth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 14:38:52 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.joshuarieken.com/2016/03/28/how-to-tell-little-white-lies-with-pivotal-tracker.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.joshuarieken.com/2016/03/28/how-to-tell-little-white-lies-with-pivotal-tracker.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
