<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Josh Rieken</title>
    <description>Software developer. Micropreneur. I love Elixir, Ruby, Neovim, RVing, and small things.
</description>
    <link>http://www.joshuarieken.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.joshuarieken.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 13:55:08 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 13:55:08 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Tell Little White Lies with Pivotal Tracker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://softwareforgood.com/estimates-lies/&quot;&gt;Estimates are always lies&lt;/a&gt;. But let’s forget about that for a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pivotaltracker.com&quot;&gt;Pivotal Tracker&lt;/a&gt; for many years and find that it still provides tremendous value. There’s an age-old debate: Which story point scale should I use when estimating? Is the default setting (Linear, or 0,1,2,3) sufficient?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s a more important question: &lt;strong&gt;What do story point values &lt;em&gt;mean?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This turns out to be pretty tricky. A little googling will quickly reveal that almost every developer has their own interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer needs to provide conceptual tools to aid our estimation efforts, not hinder them, or worse, frustrate us to the point of abandoning them altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind that there’s no such thing as perfection in Estimation Land, consider the fibonacci sequence (0,1,2,3,5,8) interpreted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0:&lt;/strong&gt; Something trivial which directly affects and is noticeable by the user (e.g., fixing a typo, altering some copy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:&lt;/strong&gt; A feature about which everything is known, and implementation is straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:&lt;/strong&gt; A feature about which everything is known, and there’s some complexity involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:&lt;/strong&gt; A somewhat fuzzy feature. There’s a good idea of how to move forward, but there’s an integration or some other aspect that may add unforeseen complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5:&lt;/strong&gt; A feature that needs to be planned. It’s too high-level and/or involves a large amount of complexity. Some exploratory work may need to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8:&lt;/strong&gt; A pie-in-the-sky feature. There’s lots of discussion, exploration and planning to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this fulfills my requirements for a useful estimation method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, consider these meta rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing above a 3 should ever be started.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that 5s and 8s should always be broken down. The resulting stories will often add up to more than 5 or 8. That’s ok.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Furthermore, &lt;strong&gt;try not to put 5s and 8s in the backlog&lt;/strong&gt;. I find they skew the overall point count. They should really be 21s and 55s to better reflect what they often turn out to be in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember: estimates are always lies. However, they can be &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; little white lies that help us inch closer to the truth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 14:38:52 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.joshuarieken.com/2016/03/28/how-to-tell-little-white-lies-with-pivotal-tracker.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.joshuarieken.com/2016/03/28/how-to-tell-little-white-lies-with-pivotal-tracker.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
